Sometimes you find yourself in a
有时你会发现自己身处
stranger's garage with a drill and a
陌生人的车库，手里拿着电钻和
dental probe so your smart glasses can
牙科探针，这时你的智能眼镜就可以
now be spy glasses. This light tells you
变成间谍眼镜了。 这个指示灯亮起表示
I'm recording but by my count thousands
我正在录制，但据我统计，成千上万的
of people are out there recording
人在录制时并
without this light. They're hiring
没有这个指示灯。 他们
people on Facebook Marketplace to drill
通过 Facebook Marketplace 雇人来钻
out the light for as much as a hundred
掉灯，费用高达一百
dollars. According to our reporting
美元。 据我们报道，
least 30 states despite Meta's attempts
尽管 Meta 试图阻止，但至少有 30 个州的商家仍在提供这项服务
to stop it.
。
&gt;&gt; When people come to you, do they ever
当人们来找你时，他们会
tell you why they want to do this?
告诉你他们为什么想做这件事吗？
&gt;&gt; No.
不，
&gt;&gt; I don't ask, they don't tell me.
我不问，他们也不告诉我。
&gt;&gt; There are lots of people doing this but
很多人都在做这件事，但
there are also a lot of questions. How
也有很多问题。
easy is it? Is it illegal? And can
这有多容易？ 这样做违法吗？ 有什么
anything be done to stop it?
办法可以阻止这种情况发生吗？
&gt;&gt; Are those filming you?
他们在拍你吗？
&gt;&gt; No, no, they're not recording.
不，不，他们没有录音。
&gt;&gt; I was going to say you don't have Meta
我本来想说你没戴Meta
glasses on.
眼镜。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's my regular glasses on.
是的，我戴的是我的普通眼镜。
&gt;&gt; It's already difficult enough to film in
在公共场所拍摄已经够难了
public. I don't want to have a blinking
。 我不想
light on my face.
脸上亮着闪烁的灯。
&gt;&gt; There are plenty of reasons someone
人们
might want to obscure the light on these
可能出于各种原因想要遮挡这款售价
$250 Meta Ray-Ban smart glasses. Here's
250 美元的 Meta Ray-Ban 智能眼镜的光线。 这是
one trend that's exploded online.
网络上迅速兴起的一种趋势。
&gt;&gt; Today I'm going to be rizzing up some
今天我要好好“招待”一下某些
people. Excuse me, you look fantastic.
人。 不好意思，你看起来棒极了。
&gt;&gt; It's called rizz camming. People hitting
这叫做rizz camming。 有人用
interaction through glasses then posting
眼镜偷偷录下搭讪过程，然后将
the videos online for millions to watch.
视频上传到网上供数百万人观看。
To be clear, we're not saying all rizz
需要澄清的是，我们并不是说所有
cammers have disabled the light or that
偷拍者都关闭了灯光，也不是说所有
everyone who's disabled the light is a
关闭灯光的人都是
rizz cammer. One journalist I talked to
偷拍者。 我采访过的一位记者这样做是为了在
Minneapolis without drawing attention to
不引起注意的情况下报道她在明尼阿波利斯的移民和海关执法局（ICE）的行动，而
the fact that she was recording. Others
她正在录音。 其他人
told me they just don't want people
告诉我，他们只是不希望在
asking questions when they're recording.
录音时有人提问。
Hey Meta, record a video.
嘿 Meta，录个视频。
&gt;&gt; Quick Ray-Ban Meta anatomy lesson. The
快速了解雷朋Meta眼镜的结构。
lens on the right side is the camera.
右侧的镜头就是相机。
The one on the left side is the light to
左侧的指示灯是
indicate recording. Meta and
录像指示灯。  Meta 和
EssilorLuxottica sold over 7 million
EssilorLuxottica 在 2025 年售出了超过 700 万
pairs of smart glasses in 2025. So I
副智能眼镜。所以我
bought a new pair of glasses to see See
买了一副新眼镜，想看看
hard it would be to turn that light off.
关掉那个灯有多难。
First, I tried a little piece of black
首先，我试着用了一小块黑色
tape and let's put it right on here. Hey
胶带，我们把它贴在这里。 嘿
Meta, record a video.
Meta，录个视频。
&gt;&gt; The capture LED is blocked. Unblock the
捕获 LED 被遮挡了。 取下
front of the glasses to use the camera.
眼镜正面的遮挡物即可使用摄像头。
&gt;&gt; Meta explicitly says on its website that
Meta 在其网站上明确表示，
if the light is covered, you'll be
如果灯光被遮挡，您将收到
notified to clear it before taking a
通知，以便在
photo or video or going live. So next, I
拍照、录像或直播之前清除遮挡物。 所以接下来，我
bought these LED blockers on Amazon.
在亚马逊上买了这些LED遮光罩。
They let just enough light through so
它们允许少量光线透过，因此
recording still works, but it can be
仍然可以进行录制，但这种光线可能会被人
noticeable, which is why there's now a
注意到，这就是为什么现在
whole cottage industry on Facebook
在 Facebook
Marketplace where people advertise
Marketplace 上出现了一个完整的产业，人们在那里出售
stealth mode where they remove the light
隐形模式，完全去除光线
entirely and make the glasses look brand
，使眼镜看起来像全新的一样
new. So I contacted one of the sellers.
。 于是我联系了其中一位卖家。
I agreed to his $100 price and he agreed
我同意了他100美元的要价，他也同意
to let us film if we didn't use his real
让我们拍摄，条件是我们不使用他的真实
name or show his face. So, let's call
姓名或露出他的脸。 那么，我们就叫
him Stealth Cam Steve.
他“隐形摄像机史蒂夫”吧。   我
&gt;&gt; Just driving to get my light removed.
只是开车去把灯拆掉。
This little light of mine.
我的这盏小灯。
Not going to let it shine.
不会让它闪耀。   是的
&gt;&gt; And yes, I brought my producer David and
，我带上了我的制片人大卫，我们
a guy from the internet in a New Jersey
在新泽西州的一个车库里与一位从网上认识的人见面之前，对他进行了背景调查
garage.
。
&gt;&gt; These are set to go.
这些都准备就绪。
&gt;&gt; Stealth Cam Steve took us through his
Stealth Cam Steve 向我们展示了他的
whole process, which he learned himself
整个制作过程，这是他
by watching others on YouTube and
通过观看 YouTube 和 TikTok 上的其他人自学的
TikTok. He taped up the glasses and left
。 他用胶带把眼镜封住，在
a little opening around the LED light.
LED灯周围留了一个小开口。
&gt;&gt; So now what I'm going to do,
所以现在我要做的，就是把
I'm going to break [snorts] the glass.
玻璃打碎[吸气]。
Breaking the glass, cleaning out the
打碎玻璃，清理
glass so that I could start drilling.
玻璃碎片，这样我就可以开始钻孔了。
So this is a a Dremel
这是一台
with a small bit.
装有小型钻头的Dremel工具。
&gt;&gt; Up.
向上。
It's gone.
它不见了。
No light.
没有灯光。
&gt;&gt; After that, he filled the little hole
之后，他
with a bit of resin, which makes it look
用一点树脂填补了小孔，使它看起来
like glass again.
又像玻璃了。
&gt;&gt; So now I put it under the UV, I dry it
现在我把它放在紫外线下，烘干
for a few seconds.
几秒钟。
So what I do is I take the paper off.
所以我把纸撕掉了。
&gt;&gt; Look at that.
瞧瞧。
&gt;&gt; And then what I'll do is I'll just
然后我会再
double-check around.
仔细核查一遍。
&gt;&gt; That's some pretty clean work.
这活儿干得真干净利落。
&gt;&gt; That's really flat and looks
它很扁平，看起来
like a lens. Hey Meta,
像个镜头。 嘿 Meta，
start recording. No light
开始录制。 手机没有反应，
and no
也没有收到任何
alert on my phone. So, no errors,
警报。 所以，没有错误，
totally able to record now.
现在可以完全录制了。
would do this service in this state.
在这个州，我并不难找到愿意提供这项服务的人。
10 that uh people that I reached out to
我联系了很多人，至少有 10 个人来帮忙
for this.
。
But,
但
what we found is that they're all over
我们发现，它们遍布
the country.
全国各地。
&gt;&gt; We searched Facebook Marketplace in
我们在 Facebook Marketplace 上搜索了
every state for this service, and we
每个州的这项服务，结果
found ads for it in 30 states. In most
在 30 个州都找到了相关广告。 在大多数
states, we found multiple listings. In
州，我们都找到了多个房源。
the New York and New Jersey area alone,
仅在纽约和新泽西地区，
there were 23 listings.
就有 23 个房源。
When I reached out to Meta, a company
当我联系 Meta 公司时，一位公司
spokesman said, "We aggressively target
发言人表示：“我们积极打击
anyone advertising tampering tools, have
任何宣传篡改工具的人，已经
removed thousands of violating ads and
删除了数千个违规广告和
Marketplace listings for these services,
Marketplace 上的此类服务列表，
and pursue legal action when
并在适当的时候采取法律行动
appropriate." After we contacted Meta
。” 在我们联系 Meta
for this story, many of the listings we
进行报道后，我们找到的许多列表都
found disappeared.
消失了。
But, plenty of device hackers are still
但是，很多设备黑客仍然能
finding ways to reach customers, and
找到接触客户的方法，而且
it's a profitable business. Prices
这是一门有利可图的生意。
nationwide range from $50 to $100 a pop,
全国各地的价格从每双 50 美元到 100 美元不等，
and many folks say they're doing
许多人表示他们
multiple pairs a day.
一天要买好几双。
&gt;&gt; Just today, how many people do you think
仅今天一天，你认为有多少人
reached out to get this done?
联系我来完成这件事？
&gt;&gt; I'd say about eight or nine people.
我估计大概有八九个人。
&gt;&gt; What Steve and the many other Meta
史蒂夫和其他许多Meta
glasses hackers are doing is not
眼镜黑客所做的事情并不
illegal. Against the Meta terms of
违法。 是否违反 Meta 的
service? Yes. As it says here, "You may
服务条款？ 是的。 正如这里所说，“您
not tamper with the glasses or otherwise
不得篡改眼镜，或以其他方式
obscure or modify any of the features on
遮蔽或修改眼镜上任何
the glasses that signal to others that
向他人表明
the glasses are recording." Meta also
眼镜正在录制的功能。”  Meta还
shared that the majority of glasses
表示，大多数眼镜
owners use their glasses as intended.
佩戴者都能按预期方式使用眼镜。
The company also said it's working with
该公司还表示，正在与
other retailers and sellers to take down
其他零售商和卖家合作，下架
items that violate the terms, like those
违反条款的商品，例如那些
LED [music] covers. But the worst thing
LED [音乐] 封面。 但
that happens if you get this service
如果您选择这项服务，最糟糕的情况
done is your warranty is voided. That's
就是您的保修失效。 这
not punishable by law. What might be
不属于法律规定的惩罚范围。
illegal is covert recording.
秘密录音可能属于违法行为。
to this. Our law firm at mwl-law.com
这其中存在极其复杂的司法管辖权差异。 我们律师事务所 mwl-law.com
publishes a chart. It's a 50-state
发布了一份图表。 这是一项针对美国50个州的
survey on recording laws. And it
录音法律调查。 它
outlines what we're looking for. And
概述了我们正在寻找的内容。 要么
there's either all-party consent states,
是所有参与方都同意的状态，这
meaning that all parties to a recorded
意味着录音对话的所有参与方都
need to consent to that. There are other
需要同意。 还有一些
states that are one-party consent state.
州实行单方同意制。
&gt;&gt; This seems to be our new reality. More
这似乎就是我们新的现实。
cameras, more microphones everywhere.
到处都是摄像头和麦克风。
And less certainty about who and what is
而且，对于谁在录音、录音内容是什么，也存在更多的不确定性
recording. The upside, people are trying
。 好的一面是，人们正在尝试
to fight back. Apps have popped up that
反抗。 已经出现了一些
use Bluetooth to scan for nearby camera
利用蓝牙技术扫描附近摄像
glasses.
头眼镜的应用程序。
One of those apps is called No
其中一款应用叫做 No
Glasshole. A throwback to Google Glass
Glasshole。 让人不禁想起谷歌眼镜
and Glassholes. The app shows the
和眼镜怪兽。 该应用程序会显示
glasses that are out of their case.
未放在眼镜盒中的眼镜。
&gt;&gt; update tomorrow that would go to
明天会发布更新，
everyone. And now we have the ability to
所有人都会收到。 现在我们有能力
tell if someone's using it. They could
知道是否有人正在使用它。 他们可以
take No Glasshole, they have the best
拿下 No Glasshole，他们拥有
engineers in the world. They could just
世界上最好的工程师。 他们完全可以将这项
build the same technology into the Meta
技术集成到 Meta
AI app. There are technical solutions to
AI 应用中。
these problems, and my goal is to like
这些问题都有技术解决方案，我的目标是推动
push them toward making these like
这些解决
solutions possible. Because what really
方案的实现。 真正让
worries me about this covert recording
我担心的是，这些偷偷录音的
crowd is that they're not just like
人不仅仅是
being rude. They're they're risking our
无礼而已。 他们正在拿我们
ability to put on like to jump into this
进入这个
new world, to like record hands-free
新世界的能力冒险，比如
videos with my kids, to travel the world
和孩子们一起录制免提视频，以及带着
with live transcription. They're not
实时转录环游世界。 它们
actually just great for me.
其实不仅仅对我有益。
&gt;&gt; And I really agree with that last point.
我非常同意最后一点。
I've been wearing Meta Ray-Bans for
我戴Meta Ray-Ban眼镜已经很多
years because they're a convenient way
年了，因为
to record without a smartphone in my
不用手里拿着智能手机就能方便地进行录音
hand. And I haven't had a problem with
。 我没遇到过
the light being on. But now, because of
灯亮着的问题。 但现在，由于
a few bad actors, any person wearing
少数不法分子的缘故，任何佩戴
these glasses may end up looking like a
这种眼镜的人最终都可能看起来像个
rizz camera, browser.
偷拍的摄像头或浏览器。
when you fell from heaven?
从天堂坠落时，你觉得疼吗？